Most people with good sense would accept that we can and should learn from accidental failures.
大多数明智的人都会认同：我们能够而且应该从意外的失败中吸取教训。
It would be impossible to progress in anything, after all, without taking the occasional misstep.
毕竟，不偶尔出点失误，做任何事都不可能取得进步。
And by understanding how we slipped, we can avoid falling in the future.
而弄清自己是怎样滑倒的，我们将来就能避免摔倒。
Few would advocate making intentional mistakes, however.
然而，很少有人会提倡故意犯错。
Yet consciously erring can promote deeper understanding and better recall.
但有意识地犯错能促进更深入的理解，增强记忆。
The phenomenon is known as the derring effect—coming from “deliberate erring”—and when applied properly, it may bring benefits in many unexpected areas of life.
这种现象被称为“故意犯错效应”（derring effect），名称源自“deliberate erring”（故意犯错）；如果运用得当，它可能在生活中许多意想不到的领域带来好处。
In one experiment carried out at the National University of Singapore, participants were given the task of learning concepts on a difficult subject.
在新加坡国立大学开展的一项实验中，参与者接到的任务是学习一门较难学科中的一些概念。
For some terms, they simply copied out the correct definition; for others, they were asked to first add an error in their description of the term before correcting the mistake.
对于一部分术语，他们只是照抄正确的定义；对于另一部分术语，他们被要求先在对术语的描述中加入一个错误，然后再改正这个错误。
Naturally, you would expect the addition of the errors to have increased unwanted confusion.
按常理，你会以为加入错误会增加不必要的困惑。
Yet the exact opposite was true: the participants who made deliberate errors learned about twice as much as the people who simply copied out the correct definitions.
然而事实恰恰相反：故意犯错的参与者学到的东西，大约是只照抄正确定义的人的两倍。
The derring effect could be applied in other situations.
故意犯错效应还可以应用于其他情境。
So a music teacher may find the addition of deliberate errors could help a student remember the right musical notes.
比如，音乐老师可能会发现，故意加入一些错误能帮助学生记住正确的音符。
Such a playful approach could fuel their creativity for composition, if the student looks for ways to develop those wrong notes into something more attractive.
如果学生设法把那些错误的音符发展成更动听的东西，这种好玩的方法就可能激发学生的作曲创造力。
It is encouraging to discover that by readily accepting our errors and wisely placing ourselves in the way of being wrong, we can in fact overcome weaknesses and rise stronger.
令人鼓舞的是，我们发现，通过欣然接受自己的错误、明智地让自己置身于可能出错的境地，其实就能克服弱点，重新站起来，变得更强。
The derring effect could be useful for many other challenges too.
故意犯错效应也可能有助于应对其他许多挑战。
If you enjoy cooking, for example, you may faithfully follow a recipe without questioning the instructions.
比如，如果你喜欢做饭，你可能会严格地照着菜谱做，而不去质疑其中的说明。
But why not try to break away from those habits and deliberately do the “wrong” thing for a change, and see where your derring takes you?
可为什么不试着摆脱这些习惯，换换花样，故意做些“错”事，看看这样故意犯错会把你带向何方呢？
If you are painting, meanwhile, you could relax one of the constraints that you usually put on your work and see what you produce.
而如果你在画画，可以把平时给自己作品设下的限制放宽一条，看看会画出些什么。
At worst, you will have refreshed and deepened your knowledge of the rules you normally apply, so that you can be even more effective next time.
往最坏处说，你也能重温自己平时所遵循的规则，并加深对它们的了解，这样下次就能更有成效。
At best, you may just find that you have discovered something completely new and unexpected, through a flash of inspiration that you would have missed with perfectionism.
往最好处说，你说不定会借着灵光一闪，发现某种全新的、意想不到的东西；而如果抱着完美主义，你就会错过这一闪而过的灵感。
Either way, your apparent missteps will have moved you a little closer to true mastery.
无论哪种情况，你那些看似失误的举动，都会让你离真正的精通更近一点。